# **Craig Neeson**

# **Frontend Engineer**

craigneeson@hotmail.co.uk 07517099522

Website: <a href="https://craigneeson.co.uk">https://craigneeson.co.uk</a>
Github: <a href="https://github.com/cneeson">https://github.com/cneeson</a>
Linkedin: <a href="https://tinyurl.com/2sn5z78a">https://tinyurl.com/2sn5z78a</a>

# **About**

Experienced front-end developer with a demonstrated history of contributing to projects used by a global user-base. Specialising in React, Vue and TypeScript, enjoys working with diverse teams to create the best possible products for users to enjoy and the cleanest possible code for developers to maintain.

# Frontend

Working on UI code is my passion in software development. I have extensive experience architecting and implementing UIs for the web and mobile using a variety development setups. I have a deep knowledge of JavaScript/Typescript and am just as comfortable working in vanilla JS as with a UI framework. I have architected web projects from the ground up and enjoy working with teams to strategise around solutions to some of the more challenging parts of UI design. I have experience working both as an individual contributor who owns the full frontend, and also as one of many team-players who all have a stake in the codebase.

# **Backend**

I also have experience contributing to monolithic and micro/serviceorientated projects in C#, Java and PHP (Laravel). As much as having accurate and up-to-date data contracts are important to me, I find it useful to have a surface-level understanding of the code behind APIs.

# Personal

In a career that is largely focused on screens, I enjoy unwinding in the evening by listening to music and (attempting) to play a bit of guitar. I also try to get into the outdoors as much as possible by running and exercising. I am a techy at heart though, and will often have a few unfinished side-projects to tinker with too.

# **Education**



# **Ulster University**

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Computing, First Class Honours Jan 2013 - Jan 2017 | 4 years

# **Technologies**

A quick round-up of technologies that I have worked with over the years.

# **Highly Proficient**

- TypeScript & JavaScript
- Vue & Nuxt
- React & React-Native
- Node
- HTML and template engines such as Handlebars and Pug
- CSS, preprocessors (SCSS/LESS), CSS-in-JS libraries (styled-components), CSS utility libs (tailwind)
- Data management and fetching libraries such as Redux/VueX and react-query
- Testing frameworks such as Jest/react-testinglibrary/Cypress
- Build tools such as Webpack, Rollup, Vite and Gulp
- CI tools such as Azure Pipelines, Heroku, Jenkins
- Monitoring services such as Sentry and Grafana
- Analytics services such as Heap Analytics, Hotjar and Google Analytics

# Working Knowledge

- Angular
- · Backend languages like PHP, C# and Java
- AWS Lambdas, SQS, SNS, Cloudfront & S3

## Where I'd like to improve

• Docker & Kubernetes

# **Experience**



#### **Ankorstore**

## Senior Frontend Engineer

Oct 2021 - Present | 3 years 4 months

- Joined Ankorstore during a period of rapid growth, scaling from 50 to 400 employees in one year. Attracted to their mission to support brick-and-mortar shops against large online competitors.
- Worked with Vue and Nuxt to develop features for marketplace, order-fulfillment, and backoffice platforms, focusing on shipping and logistics. Key projects included enabling users to compare and select carrier quotes, track shipments, and visualize stock movements.
- Participated in company-wide projects such as re-brandings, Vue to Nuxt migrations, offer-system implementations, and new business model changes.
- Collaborated closely with product and data engineers to deliver analytics tracking for all features, allowing a data-driven approach to product development.



# Locate a Locum

## Software Developer

Oct 2019 - Oct 2021 | 2 years

- Led the modernization of UI for this healthcare start-up's web and mobile apps, setting ambitious yet achievable technical goals that transformed UI development.
- Worked with developers to set front-end standards and upskilled team members to enable faster feature development and tackle existing tech debt more effectively.
- Drove key architecture changes to allow us to move the LAL platform from a legacy web-app stack to a partially serverside-rendered React stack.
- Established LALs first fully documented React component library, working with a newly hired UX designer to refresh the Locate a Locum brand.
- Developed maintainable patterns for data retrieval and caching from our API, promoting better separation of server and client state and reducing boilerplate code.
- Identified opportunities to abstract duplicated data-fetching code into NPM packages which are now shared between React and React Native repos.
- Introduced TypeScript to UI repositories, enhancing code robustness and reducing bugs. Currently, 40% of the main codebase is in TS.
- Alongside process improvement, I delivered new web and mobile modules for employee leave management, scheduling, clock-in, and payroll processing.



#### Flexera

#### **UI Engineer & Associate UI Engineer**

Sep 2018 - Nov 2019 | 1 year 2 months

- Worked as part of a global team to build UIs for 8 different products, used by many of the worlds "Fortune 50" companies.
- Standardised design token usage and UI behaviours via a component library, balancing design consistency and flexibility for future use cases. Read more here.
- Worked with various acquisition teams, gaining exposure to different UI development approaches and technology stacks.
- Worked across many interesting and technically challenging products including a portal to visualise one of the worlds largest technology asset datasets, a dashboard
  to visualise and optimise Azure, AWS & GCP cloud resource costs, and a network-security monitoring system.



### Nitec Solutions

# Software Developer

Nov 2017 - Oct 2018 | 11 months

- · Worked in a small consultancy team to deliver full-stack solutions for many businesses in Northern Ireland.
- Delivered end-to-end sales, billing and production management systems for two large concrete factories. The systems integrated directly with production-line
  firmware and tracked vehicles in real-time, allowing coordinators to have a birds eye view of their operations.
- Developed internal processes, including CI pipelines, private package registries, and a modular front-end component system using vanilla JavaScript and Handlebars.



# **Liberty Information Technology**

#### Associate Software Engineer

Jun 2017 - Dec 2017 | 6 months

- Worked on an integrations team to build the highly scalable infrastructure behind a greenfield insurance product.
- Gained exposure to many different languages (Kotlin, TypeScript & Scala) and AWS resources (Lambda, SQS & SNS) due to the sprawling micro-service architecture.



# Nitec Solutions Placement Developer

Jun 2015 - Oct 2016 | 1 year 4 months

- Gained exposure to older stacks (classic ASP, Microsoft Silverlight) as well as newer ones (.NET MVC apps, SPAs) due to the varying range of client projects and setups.
- Developed an agent program and UI to monitor backup status of client servers and desktops. Later, built the first version of a customer portal for real-time backup visualization, which remains in daily use by many of Nitec's customers.

